# **Bryan Kowal**

Glassboro, NJ 856-906-4425 linkedin.com/in/bryan-kowal

badboybry9000@gmail.com https://bryan-kowal.netlify.app

#### **SUMMARY**

Skilled full stack Application Developer with 20+ years of well-rounded experience creating custom, unit tested web and desktop apps. Strong troubleshooting skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Angular/TypeScript expert. Laravel/PHP and SQL adept.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEC 2003 - PRESENT

Application Developer, Household Metals, Inc., Philadelphia, PA

- Developed product configuration app to keep existing and attract new customers
- Overhauled product ordering app to decrease bugs and increase usability
- Developed order form for new sliding door product line
- Automated database update process reducing update time from hours to minutes
- Developed order tracking app to track manufacturing processes resulting in more on time orders among other benefits
- Developed bar code scanner Android app to provide photographic documentation of the manufacturing process
- Streamlined the box labeling process and polished the label format for completed orders awaiting pick up
- Developed product labels to assist end users with product identification
- Developed custom document scanner app to make paperwork distribution more efficient

SEP 2002 - NOV 2003

Graphics / UI Designer, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

- Designed computer lab documentation website
- Trained other designers on Adobe Flash

SEP 2001 - MAR 2002

Technical Support Agent, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

- Rescued many faculty, staff, and student computers
- Trained other agents on troubleshooting strategies

## **SKILLS**

```
Angular • TypeScript • JavaScript • RxJS • NgRx • Nx • Ionic • Unit Testing • Jest • Cypress • PHP • Laravel • MySQL • HTML5 • CSS • Bootstrap • C# • SAP Crystal Reports
```

## **EDUCATION**

2003

Drexel University, Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Science, Information Science and Technology